Guide to the Peter C. Allen Collection Documenting Student Demonstrations at Stanford SC0157
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Peter C. Allen collection documenting student demonstrations at Stanford
1965-1971
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Allen, Peter C. (Peter Carr)
SC0157
1.75 Linear Feet
Research notes, reports, Stanford news releases, and Peter Allen's draft of the first five chapters of a projected thirteen for a study entitled, "Demonstrations at Stanford, autumn 1965-spring 1971." Materials about campus demonstrations were assembled by Allen, University Editor. Also includes news releases, memos, etc. regarding minorities, anti-military sentiment, and racist policies.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Peter C. Allen, 1977.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Peter Allen received A.B. in Economics from Stanford in 1936 and in 1938 received an A.B. in English, also from Stanford; served as editor of the Stanford Review (1946-1952), Director of News and Publications (1952-1961), later the Publications Service (1961-1965), University Editor (1965-1976), and University Editor emeritus (1977-2001) at Stanford.
Description of the Collection
Research notes, reports, Stanford news releases, and Peter Allen's draft of the first five chapters of a projected thirteen for a study entitled, "Demonstrations at Stanford, autumn 1965-spring 1971." Materials about campus demonstrations in the first accession were assembled by Allen, University Editor. Also includes news releases, memos, etc. regarding minorities, anti-military sentiment, and racist policies.
Notes.; News releases.; Journalists.; Student movements -- California -- Stanford.; Student demonstrations.; Reports.; Students -- Political activity.; Stanford University. Office of Public Affairs; Stanford University. University Relations; Stanford University. News and Publications Service; Allen, Peter C. (Peter Carr); Allen, Peter C. (Peter Carr); Pitzer, Kenneth S.; Doty, Andrew M.
- Papers
  - Allen, Peter C. “Demonstrations at Stanford, Autumn 1965-Spring 1971.” Draft of first five chapters of projected ten chapters (never completed). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - “Disruption documents.” Assembled to accompany Allen manuscript. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - “The Student Sit-in at Stanford University.” Typescript, May 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - “Report of the Stanford-S.R.I. Committee”, April 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Remarks: President Kenneth S. Pitzer, Stanford Alumni Conference,” typescript, May 17, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - U. S. Senate. Committee on Government Operations. Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations [McClellan Subcommittee]. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News releases, photocopies of correspondence relating to subpoena issued to Pres. Pitzer to identify members of any organization taking part in campus disruptions at Stanford (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - McClellan Subcommittee. “Riots, Civil and Criminal Disorders, and Disruptions on College Campuses,” Stenographic transcript of hearings, excerpts relating to Stanford (8085-8376) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Doty, Andrew M. (Public Affairs office). “The Cost of Violence and Disruption at Stanford University, 1967-68, 1968-69 and 1969-70.” (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Offset copy of draft report and final copy, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - News releases, 1 April 1970-31 July 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - News releases, 2 December 1970-31 March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News releases, 5 April 1971-7 September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - News releases, 21 September 1971-21 December 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - News releases, 4 January 1972-5 July 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - News releases, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - News releases, speeches, and other miscellaneous documents, May 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Document sets identified as: I Hospital-Medical School; II Minorities; III Franklin/Lodge/Comp Center; IV Anti-Military; V Employees (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - News releases, speeches, and other miscellaneous documents, 1965, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - News releases, speeches, and other miscellaneous documents, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - News releases, speeches, and other miscellaneous documents, 1972-73 (Box 2, Folder 4)